all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh... *
-*哦...*
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
所有：海绵宝宝！
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
* *
**
narrator: Submitted for
your approval:
旁白：提交给
您的认可：
Bikini Bottom, teeming with life
比基尼泳裤，充满生机
and many strange tales.
以及许多奇怪的故事。
The story you're about to see
happened
你即将看到的故事
发生了
on one very weird
and unusual day,
在一个非常奇怪的事情上
和不寻常的一天，
when the town crossed over
into...
当城镇穿越时
进入...
This, sir, is penosterous!
先生，这太阴险了！
I demand restitution!
我要求赔偿！
- Sir, I've told you
- 先生，我已经告诉过你了
we don't sell balloons!
- I want to speak
我们不卖气球！
- 我想说话
to the manager.
I bet he knows
给经理。
我打赌他知道
where the balloons are.
气球在哪里。
Balloons?
气球？
Aw, it's just a stupid old bus.
噢，这只是一辆愚蠢的旧公共汽车。
- Give me that!
- 给我那个！
- On behalf of Tram's Travels,
- 代表 Tram's Travels，
I'd like to welcome you
to Bikini Bottom.
我想欢迎你
到比基尼底部。
I'd also like to take a moment
to familiarize you
我也想花点时间
让你熟悉
with the area.
The restrooms are to the left.
与该地区。
卫生间在左边。
Hey, I have to go too!
嘿嘿，我也得走了！
Hey, mister?
You dropped your hat.
嘿，先生？
你把帽子掉了。
Oh, come on!
哦，来吧！
- Okay, I'll...
keep it warm for you.
- 好吧，我会...
为你保暖。
I could be a tour guide!
我可以当导游！
Ooh, I could be a tour guide?
哦，我可以当导游吗？
- That's what I said!
- 这就是我说的！
Wow!
Everything is so amazing!
哇！
一切都是那么奇妙！
Hello, are you the tour guide?
你好，请问你是导游吗？
- Uh...uh!
- 呃……呃！
Yes, I am.
All right, everyone,
我是。
好吧，大家，
settle down.
My name is Patrick
安家。
我的名字是帕特里克
and I'll be your guide
to the wonderful world
我会成为你的向导
到美好的世界
of Bikini Bottom.
的比基尼底部。
Please take small children
firmly by the hand.
请携带小孩
用手牢牢地握住。
And we're walking,
we're walking...
而我们走着，
我们正在步行...
- I feel like I'm gonna burst!
- 我感觉我要爆炸了！
- Our first landmark
is the kissing stone
- 我们的第一个地标
是接吻石
of the ancients.
It is said to bring good luck
古人的。
据说可以带来好运
to all who smooch it.
致所有亲吻它的人。
Brash!
傲慢！
- Amazing!
- 惊人的！
- Another ancient
and mysterious landmark
- 另一个古老的
和神秘的地标
is this hole
that I dug yesterday.
是这个洞吗
我昨天挖的。
It fits my butt!
很适合我的屁股！
Now you try it.
现在你试试吧。
- Whoa!
Golly.
- 哇！
发誓。
Mine too.
我的也是。
- On your left is a kid
who, legend has it,
- 你左边是一个孩子
传说中的谁，
used to have an ice cream cone.
以前有一个蛋卷冰淇淋。
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- Amazing!
- 惊人的！
- This guy called me
a bad word once.
- 这个人打电话给我
一次说脏话。
You were trying to eat
你本来想吃东西
my mailbox!
我的邮箱！
- I thought it was meatloaf!
- 我以为是肉饼！
- Kids, escort these "gentlemen"
to the door.
- 孩子们，护送这些“先生们”
到门口。
kids: With pleasure!
孩子们：很高兴！
kids:
- Amazing!
孩子们：
- 太棒了！
- Booyah!
- 嘘！
- Coming up ahead is the home
of SpongeBob SquarePants,
- 前面就是家
海绵宝宝，
the fry cook.
- Oh, my gosh.
炒菜厨师。
- 哦，天哪。
That sounds excitin'!
听起来很令人兴奋！
- We have begun our descent.
- 我们已经开始下降。
Everyone please gather
请大家集合
all your belongings
and follow me single file.
你所有的物品
并跟随我单行。
- Amazing!
- 惊人的！
- This is my best friend
SpongeBob.
- 这是我最好的朋友
海绵宝宝。
As you can see,
he sucks his thumb
正如你所看到的，
他吮吸拇指
when he sleeps.
当他睡觉的时候。
- Oh-- wait, that's me.
- 哦 - 等等，那是我。
[alarm clock ringing,
Patrick shouting]
【闹钟响了，
帕特里克大喊]
Yes, I like
sweet potatoes, thank you.
是的，我喜欢
红薯，谢谢。
- My internal alarm clock says
- 我的内部闹钟说
it's time for morning lunch.
现在是吃午餐的时间了。
Everyone, follow me.
大家跟我来吧。
And we're tiptoeing...
tiptoeing...
而我们却踮起脚尖...
踮着脚尖...
- Amazing.
- 惊人的。
- The tour will resume shortly,
everyone.
- 巡演将很快恢复，
大家。
And also, uh,
还有，呃，
I think the mayo
was spoiled.
我认为蛋黄酱
被宠坏了。
- This is Squidward the cashier.
- 这是收银员章鱼哥。
- And yes, those moles are huge.
- 是的，那些痣很大。
- And stay out!
- 留在外面！
Late for work,
上班迟到，
late for work, late for work.
上班迟到，上班迟到。
- Late for work, late for work!
- 上班迟到，上班迟到！
- Ooh, time for second lunch!
- 哦，第二顿午餐时间到了！
Everyone, follow that Bob!
大家跟着鲍勃走吧！
Yah!
And we're running.
啊！
我们正在跑步。
We're running...
我们正在跑...
This is the world-famous
Krusty Krab!
这就是举世闻名的
蟹堡王！
* *
**
- Hey!
- Now, this is Plankton,
- 嘿！
- 现在，这是浮游生物，
who's always trying to steal
the Krabby Patty.
谁总是想偷东西
蟹肉饼。
So, we step on him!
所以，我们踩他！
Ouch!
哎哟!
Try it, everyone.
It's fun.
大家试试吧。
很有趣。
- Oh, my goodness.
Can I?!
- 哦，我的天啊。
我可以吗？
- That is fun!
- 这很有趣！
- Next stop is
the Krusty kitchen.
- 下一站是
库斯蒂厨房。
- If you look to your left,
you'll see SpongeBob preparing
- 如果你向左看，
你会看到海绵宝宝正在准备
his fresh
and delicious ingredients
他的新鲜
和美味的食材
to be cooked alive.
- Oh, just doing my thing.
被活活煮熟。
- 哦，只是做我的事。
- That's amazing!
- 太棒了！
- Oh, shucks,
I'm just getting warmed up.
- 哦，糟糕，
我刚刚热身。
Uh-huh!
嗯嗯！
Yeah!
是的！
Eh, eh?
呃，呃？
Ooh!
哦！
* *
**
- And this magical place
- 还有这个神奇的地方
is where all the food ends up.
是所有食物最终的归宿。
And if you do this...
如果你这样做...
This happens!
发生这种情况！
- Stay away from me toilets!
- 离我厕所远点！
- Gol, this is the best tour
I've ever taken!
- Gol，这是最好的旅行
我曾经拿过！
- And the best is yet to come!
- Oh!
- 最好的还在后头！
- 哦！
If you look to your left...
如果你向左看...
- Hup, hup, hup, hup...
- You'll miss
- 哈、哈、哈、哈……
- 你会想念的
everything on your right.
一切都在你的右边。
Oops, almost forgot
my plant food.
哎呀差点忘了
我的植物性食物。
- Under your belly is
the outside
- 你的肚子下面是
外面
of Sandy's tree dome.
桑迪的树顶。
- It's so beautiful.
- 太漂亮了。
I wish we could see the inside.
我希望我们能看到里面。
Don't worry.
I have a key.
不用担心。
我有一把钥匙。
Everyone, watch your step.
大家注意脚下。
Sandy Cheeks and her tree
both have roots in Texas.
桑迪·奇克斯和她的树
两者都起源于德克萨斯州。
The dome overhead was designed
to keep out the water.
穹顶的顶部设计
以防止水进入。
This makes the air
too dry to survive in...
这使得空气
太干燥而无法生存...
For water-breathers like us.
对于我们这样的水呼吸者来说。
Luckily, we all have on
our water helmets,
幸运的是，我们都有
我们的水头盔，
or else we'd all be
in big trouble right about now.
否则我们都会
现在遇到大麻烦了。
both:
两个都：
- Uh-oh!
- 呃哦！
And we're running,
we're running!
而我们正在奔跑，
我们在跑！
'Cause we're expiring, expiring!
因为我们就要过期了，过期了​​！
- Ooh, it's time
- 噢，是时候了
for third lunch.
- Everyone, follow my belly.
第三顿午餐。
- 大家跟着我的肚子走。
- Aw, looks like
you plant critters
- 哦，看起来像
你种植小动物
could use a little water.
可以用一点水。
Whoa!
哇！
* *
**
Patrick!
帕特里克！
- This will probably be
the last stop on our tour.
- 这可能会是
我们旅行的最后一站。
Each one of these gravestones
这些墓碑中的每一块
has an amazing secret
underneath.
有一个惊人的秘密
下面。
There's people
living down there!
还有人
住在下面！
Hello.
你好。
- This is my old pal Ribeye,
everyone.
大家。
Ribeye, this is everyone!
肋眼，这就是大家！
- Wow, you're a dead guy.
I love it!
- 哇，你死定了。
我喜欢它！
- Well, any friend of Patrick's
is a friend of...
- 好吧，帕特里克的任何朋友
是...的朋友
- Oh, my goodness.
- 哦，我的天啊。
Let me try to...
让我尝试...
arm bone connected to the...
臂骨连接到...
- The management
- 管理层
strongly advises that you...
强烈建议您...
run away!
逃跑！
There's a disturbance
at the cemetery
有扰乱
在墓地
and some of us
are trying to sleep!
和我们中的一些人
正在努力睡觉！
- I'm sorry, Ribeye!
- 对不起，肋眼！
- And on your left,
the Bikini Bottom post office.
- 在你的左边，
比基尼泳裤邮局。
On your right is a zombie
chasing the guys
你的右边有一个僵尸
追那些家伙
who stole my hat!
谁偷了我的帽子！
- Patrick, you gotta hide!
There's an angry mob...
- 帕特里克，你得躲起来！
那里有一群愤怒的暴徒...
Coming for you.
They're here.
来找你了
他们来了。
- They done busted my dome!
- They ripped me up!
- 他们毁掉了我的圆顶！
- 他们把我撕碎了！
- They got pictures of me naked!
- 他们有我的裸体照片！
- No one wants to see
your moles.
- 没有人愿意看到
你的痣。
crowd: Ew!
众人：哎呀！
- Officer!
- 军官！
That guy's camera took pictures
那个人的相机拍了照片
of me Krabby Patty ingredients.
我的蟹肉饼配料。
And I want that film,
before Plankton gets it!
我想要那部电影
在浮游生物得到它之前！
- Way ahead of you, Krabs.
- 远远领先于你，蟹蟹。
But there's no film
in this camera at all.
但没有电影
在这台相机里。
all: Huh?
- That's strange.
全体：啊？
- 这很奇怪。
- Sorry for the
misunderstandin', everybody,
- 抱歉
大家误会了
but I didn't take
any pictures today.
但我没有采取
今天有什么照片。
I don't even have a camera.
我什至没有相机。
crowd: Huh?!
众人：啊？！
- In fact...
- 实际上...
I'm not even here.
我什至都不在这里。
- Um...uh...
- 嗯...呃...
And we're backing away,
and backing away,
而我们正在后退，
并后退，
and backing away!
并后退！
narrator: You see?
I told you.
旁白：你看到了吗？
我告诉你了。
Things always get weird
in "The Tidal Zone."
事情总是变得奇怪
在《潮汐区》中。
- Amazing!
- 惊人的！
* *
**